[
    {
        "question": "How many Cricket world cups does India have?",
        "options": ["One", "Two", "Three", "Four"],
        "answer": "Two"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first President of India?",
        "options": ["Dr.APJ Abdul Kalam", "Mahatma Gandhi", "Dr.Rajendra Prasad", "Jawaharlal Nehru"],
        "answer": "Dr.Rajendra Prasad"

    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of India?",
        "options": ["Dr Zakir HUssain", "Jawaharlal Nehru", "Dr.Rajendra Prasad", "Sir Syed Ahmad Khan"],
        "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru"

    },
    {
        "question": "Name of the first university of India?",
        "options": ["Nalanda University", "Taxshila University", "Jawahar University", "Dronacharya University"],
        "answer": "Nalanda University"

    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian state has the least literacy rate?",
        "options": ["Bihar", "Rajasthan", "Arunachal Pradesh", "Orissa"],
        "answer": "Bihar"

    },
    {
        "question": "Name of the first deputy Prime Minister of India?",
        "options": ["R.N. Shukla", "V.R. Gill", "Sardar Vallabh Bhai Patel", "D.B. Mahawar"],
        "answer": "Sardar Vallabh Bhai Patel"

    },
    {
        "question": "Name of first Space Tourist of India?",
        "options": ["DP Mahadevan", "Santosh George", "Niel Arm Strong", "V.R. Gill"],
        "answer": "Sardar Vallabh Bhai Patel"

    },
    {
        "question": "Name of the First Indian Prime Minister who resigned from Office?",
        "options": ["Indira Gandhi", "Moraji Desai", "Jawahar Lal Nehru", "Rajiv Gandhi"],
        "answer": "Moraji Desai"

    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the capital of Arunachal Pradesh?",
        "options": ["Itanagar", "Dispur", "Imphal", "Panaji"],
        "answer": "Itanagar"

    },
    {
        "question": "What is the state flower of Haryana?",
        "options": ["Rhododendron", "Lotus", "Golden Shower", "Not Declared"],
        "answer": "Lotus"

    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following states is not located in the North?",
        "options": ["Himachal Pradesh", "Jammu and Kashmir", "Haryana", "Jharkhand"],
        "answer": "Jharkhand"
        
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following state, the main language is Khasi?",
        "options": ["Mizoram", "Nagaland", "Meghalaya", "Tripura"],
        "answer": "Meghalaya"

    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the largest coffee-producing state of India?",
        "options": ["Kerala", "Karnataka", "Arunachal Pradesh", "Tamil Nadu"],
        "answer": "Karnataka"
        
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country gifted the 'Statue of Liberty' to USA in 1886?",
        "options": ["France", "Canada", "Brazil", "England"],
        "answer": "France"

    },
    {
        "question": "Dead Sea is located between which two countries?",
        "options": ["Jordan and Sudan", "Jordan and Israel", "Turkey and UAE", "UAE and Egypt"],
        "answer": "Jordan and Israel"

    },
    {
        "question": "In which ocean 'Bermuda Triangle' region is located?",
        "options": ["Indian", "Pacific", "Atlantic", "Arctic"],
        "answer": "Atlantic"

    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is known as the 'playground of Europe'?",
        "options": ["Austria", "Holland", "Switzerland", "Italy"],
        "answer": "Switzerland"

    },
    {
        "question": "Which continent has the highest number of countries?",
        "options": ["Asia", "Europe", "North America", "Africa"],
        "answer": "Switzerland"

    },
    
]